# AZEEZ BABARINDE

# Data Analyst

Data Analyst with a background in science and research. Experienced in presenting complex information in an understandable and engaging way. Completed analysis projects across multiple fields, including health care, engineering, agriculture, ecommerce, logistics and chemical regulations.

■ babarindeazeez.s@gmail.com

Perlin, Germany

zeezki.github.io

+4915218174952

in linkedin.com/in/azeezbabarinde

github.com/zeezki

# **EDUCATION**

# **Data Analytics Certification Program,**

CareerFoundry

06/2021 - 10/2021 Berlin, Germany

# Masters of Science in Environmental and Resource Management,

Brandenburg University of Technology 09/2019 - 09/2023 Cottbus, Germany

# Diploma in Web Design,

HIIT Plc

04/2016 - 07/2016 Ikeja, Nigeria

# Bachelor of Agriculture (Soil Science and Land Management),

Federal University of Agriculture
09/2009 - 11/2014 Abeokuta, Nigeria

#### Computer Systems Technician (Diploma),

Michelon Computer Institute 10/2007 - 06/2008 Lagos, Nigeria

# SKILLS / TOOLS

- Advanced Analytics
- Data Visualization (Tableau, Data studio, Power BI)
- Python (Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Scipy, Seaborn)
- SQL (GBQ, PostgreSQL)
- Advanced Excel (Pivot table/charts, VBA & Macros)
- MS Office (Excel, PowerPoint, Words)
- Google Workspace(Docs, Sheets, Slides)
- Story telling with data
- Machine Learning (Supervised and Unsupervised)
- Hypothesis testing
- SAP
- Ticket Support (JIRA)
- HTML / CSS

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Product Analyst**

Amscan Europe Kirchheim(Teck), Germany 11/2023 - Present

- Analyzed various data for strategic product range optimization
- Contributed to diverse product data management projects, enhancing organizational efficiency and data management processes
- Evaluated party items', providing actionable recommendations to increase sales effectively

### **Data Manager / Analyst**

JTI (Japan Tobacco International) Trier, Germany 07/2022 - 11/2023

- Developed data extraction tool for SDS managers to reduce manual data entry time by over 95%
- Built a visualization tool to monitor the safety data sheets requests on various KPIs
- Created an automation tool to optimize manual chemical inventory calculation, reducing task time by over 90%

# **Business Analyst - Internship**

Wayfair Berlin, Germany 01/2022 - 07/2022

- Provided excellent customer services and training on tooluse to Suppliers and warehouse managers for conversion.
- Created a visualizations tool to give visibility over late orders for the company's warehouse.
- Developed a dashboard report to show which carriers/ suppliers were the top contributor to the company's main KPIs changes from week over week.

#### **Data Analyst**

Self-employed - Freelance 08/2020 - 08/2021

 Performed cleansing, processing, and validation on data to analyze, to ensure its quality.

#### **Data Analyst**

Stanfrey Engineering Limited 12/2016 - 07/2020

 Conveyed analysis results through reports, dashboards, and presentations.

# **PROJECTS**

# EA Sports FIFA player ratings

Open exploratory analysis to determine FIFA player rating factors.

## **LANGUAGES**

English – Native User Deutsch – A2